# 在兄弟家搞了幾隻雞 如果現在不宰掉的話
We've got a couple of pheasants from my buddy. If we leave them any longer here,
# 很容易瘦掉的哦
they would easily get skinny, you know.
# 現在都放了差不多一天啦
They've been here for almost a day already.
# 它們都不吃不喝
But they don't, nor drink.
# 可能不適應這裡的環境
Perhaps they can't adapt to this place here.
# 一個一個來
One by one,
# 一天吃一個
we eat one every day.
# 剛剛好
Perfect!
# 好啦 我把雞抓下來
Alright! Let me catch the pheasant down here.
# 你看
Look!
# 我都還沒吃你就想吃
How dare you wanna eat before me!
# 你看 現在這個毛
Look! Now the feather,
# 乾啦
has been dried.
# 很漂亮哦
It's so pretty.
# 這是他家養的 七彩山雞
This is a pheasant, that he raises.
# 很快的 別叫
It won't take long. Don't yelp!
# 刀我都磿利了
I've already sharpened the knife.
# 你看
Look!
# 這個雞
This pheasant,
# 白白淨淨的哦
is as white as snow.
# 還是很不錯的
It's really not bad.
# 這沒甚麼
There's hardly,
# 沒甚麼油言個雞 全部是瘦肉
there's hardly any fat. It has only lean meat,
# 皮加瘦肉加骨頭
skin and meat and bones.
# 等下我用 用來烤 (註︰這裡一直都似乎是打算一般的烤，所以用"Grill"，到後來下雨才決定用烤爐)
Let's, let's grill it in a while.
# 烤來吃
Let's have it grilled.
# 好啦 把它內 內臟清理一下
Alright. Let me remove, remove its guts,
# 拿個竹竿
fetch a bamboo stick,
# 串著
skew it,
# 就這樣烤
then grill it right away.
# 絕對好吃
Good taste is guaranteed.
# 你看 這個雞
Look! This pheasant,
# 都沒甚麼肉臟的
there are not so many guts.
# 這個雞屁股不要
I don't want the butt.
# 來 給 小狗吃
C'mon! Give it, to the doggy.
# 你看 這個是公雞哦 它有兩個蛋
Look! This is male. It has two balls,
# 還有一個心
and also a heart.
# 等下我拿竹竿把它 這樣綁起來再烤
Let me get a bamboo stick, tie it up right there, and then grill it.
# 要打一下花刀
I need to make some patterns here.
# 就是 意思就是割它幾刀
That is, it means, slicing it a few times.
# 就是叫打花刀
And it's called "making a pattern".
# 如果不打花刀的話等一下
If there are no patterns, it would,
# 它就 就沒甚麼鹽
it wouldn't, it wouldn't be enough salt.
# 割它幾刀
Slice it a few times.
# 這邊也是
This side too
# 這個爪子我看一下 怎麼弄
The feet. Let me see. What should I do?
# 這個翹得太起來 這個腳
They're too pointed, the feet.
# 這個腳翹那麼高
The feet are so pointed.
# 乾脆把它砍了
Why not just chop them off?
# 塞到它肚子裡面去算了
Stuff them into the belly, that's it!
# 待會竹竿把它穿起來就好啦 我去腌一下它
Get a bamboo stick, skew it up and it's done. Let me marinate it.
# 不腌一下
Otherwise,
# 沒有鹽味
there wouldn't be any salty taste.
# 你看 這個雞
Look! This pheasant
# 直接把它放在這大盆裡面去
Let me simply put it into the big pot right away,
# 給它按一下摩 加點生薑給它
and then give it a massage, and give it some ginger.
# 加了生薑再搞 鹽
After ginger, put some salt.
# 加點這個鹽
Put some, you know, some salt.
# 少搞一點
Not too much
# 可以啦
Alright!
# 那鹽 袋子不好倒
The salt, the opening of the bag makes things hard.
# 再搞點料酒
And also some cooking wine.
# 搞完料酒搞醬油
After cooking wine, put some soy sauce
# 多搞點
More!
# 搞了醬油 再搞點油
After soy sauce, put some oil
# 再給它抹一抹 抹一抹身子
Then wipe it, wipe its body.
# 好啦 先腌一下 腌個半個小時
Alright! Marinate for a while first, for half an hour.
# 腌個半個小時
Marinate it for half an hour.
# 綁在烤架子上
Then tie it onto the grill.
# 我去搞個竹竿
I'm gonna fetch a bamboo stick.
# 你看 天上又那個烏 好多烏雲啦
Look! The dark, the sky is covered with dark cloud now.
# 都烏雲密布啦
It's heavily clouded now.
# 來把這個枱到 枱到可邊去
Come and let's take, take this one to the riverside.
# 這個
With this one,
# 抬到河邊去就肯定烤的到吧 我就不信
at the riverside, I can certainly roast it, right? There's no rain,
# 大水會把這個沖走
that can wash it away.
# 下再大雨都不怕 蓋在那裡就行啦
No heavy rain can stop it. Cover everything inside the oven, that's it.
# 等一下來 等一下
A moment, a moment
# 看一下會甚麼東西來
Let's see what else we need to bring.
# 炭 準備好炭來
Charcoal, get the charcoal ready!
# 你看 說下雨就下雨 幸我好我沒出去
Look! The rain pours without any warning. Fortunately, I'm still here.
# 要不然全部 要不然
Otherwise all, otherwise,
# 全部都淋成落湯雞
we would all get soaked.
# 你看 下了十幾鐘左右 現在又天晴啦
Look! After ten minutes, the sun shines again.
# 把它抬到河邊去
Let's take it to the riverside.
# 更有
It's more,
# 更有那種 更有那種感覺
it's more, like, it's more, atmospheric.
# 抬這個
Take it,
# 我們就先把這個給 抬過去 還要 還要帶甚麼東西
let's take it first, take it over there. And then, what else?
# 把這個 把這個雞
The, the pheasant
# 你看 勾起來
Look! Hook it,
# 還有兩個爪子
together with the two feet.
# 勾在這裡
Hook it here.
# 你看
Look!
# 架在這裡就可以啦
Place it here and that's it.
# 現在下雨都不怕啦
It doesn't matter even if it rains.
# 下再大的雨都不怕
It doesn't matter how heavily it rains.
# 來 把它蓋起來
C'mon! Cover it.
# 這樣就可以啦
It should be fine now.
# 隨便下 下大一點 無所謂
C'mon! Rain! Rain heavily! I don't care!
# 別發水就行 一發水的話 把這個都沖走了就麻煩了
But don't flood. It would be too bad if the oven is washed away.
# 天都 好黑了 這個天
It's, so dark. What kind of weather is it?
# 找個地方來躲雨
Let's get a shelter somewhere.
# 放在這裡烤
Leave it here.
# 烤半個小時我再過來
I'll come back in half an hour.
# 先回去
Let's go back, first.
# 先回去 玩一下手機
Go back first. Cell phone time
# 這 天好黑呀
Well, it's really dark.
# 有點 有點擔心
I'm a bit, a bit worried.
# 雞倒無所謂 別把鍋沖走了
I don't care about the pheasant. Don't wash the oven away.
# 現在沒有下
It's not raining now.
# 現在又不下雨
It stops raining again.
# 等一下回去 回去一下等下我再倒回來就可以
Let's get back in a moment. We get back, and then we can come back here later.
# 你看 這樣多方便啊 火又不用看
Look! Isn't it super convenient? I don't even to take care of it.
# 全自動的
It's full-automatic.
# 好了我就過來吃就行了
I only need to come when it's done.
# 應該 四十五分鐘 就可以開鍋
I think, it will be done, in forty five minutes.
# 過了半個小時了 我來看一下
Half an hour has passed. I come and have a look.
# 誒呦 是不是火燒了
Ayo! Is it burnt?
# 都這樣子了
What a mess!
# 都有點火燒了
It's really a bit burnt.
# 小黑聞到香味它都來啦
Blacky is here, attracted by the smell.
# 是不是小黑
Am I right? Blacky
# 我摘點 摘點這個葉子
I pick some, pick some leaves here.
# 我提起來看一下 要不然會燙到手
I wanna pick it up and have a look. It may burn my hands.
# 有片葉子就不怕了
But it's fine with the leaves.
# 幸好沒火燒
So lucky that it's not yet burnt.
# 加點這個醬汁去
Put some more sauce here.
# 好慢啊這個 直接倒了
It's so slow. Pour it right away.
# 這樣就 沒那麼容易燒焦
Then, it wouldn't get burnt so easily.
# 再去烤一下
Roast it for a few more moments.
# 再烤個十多分鐘
Roast it for another ten to twenty minutes,
# 就差不多啦
then it should be done.
# 好大猛的火哦
The fire is really strong.
# 現在都有兩百多度 你看
It's more than two hundred degrees now. Look!
# 慢慢烤
Let's take our time.
# 再烤十分鐘 等下我再過來
Roast it for another ten minutes. I'll be right back.
# 小黑
Blacky!
# 是不是想吃
You want some pheasant?
# 我鍋先洗乾淨
I wash the pot first.
# 等下直接裝就可以了
Then I can simply put the pheasant here.
# 小黑
Blacky!
# 來 我拉你下來
C'mon! I pull you down.
# 你拉我上去
Or you pull me up.
# 差點把你扯下來
I almost pulled you down.
# 你看 那裡冒煙啦 肯定熟了
Look! I can see the smoke there. It must be done now.
# 哇 好香
Wa! It smells so good!
# 看一下
Go and have a look!
# 燒黑了
It's burnt.
# 虧大了 哇
Too bad! Wa!
# 賠了一隻雞
A pheasant is wasted.
# 應該還可以吃
I think it's still edible.
# 你看 還可以吃哦
Look! It's still edible.
# 沒有
It's not,
# 沒有完全燒焦
it's not yet completely burnt.
# 現在就熟了吧
I bet it's done now.
# 雞腿吃一下
Let me have a leg.
# 誒呀 不給我吃是不是
Eya! You wanna stop me from eating, don't you?
# 不給我吃直接咬了
Then I'll simply bite it.
# 很香哦
It smells really great!
# 酥酥的 脆脆的
It's crispy, and crusty.
# 這個肉 跟牛肉乾一樣
The meat, is just like beef jerky.
# 嗯 好香哦
Um! It smells so good!
# 你看
Look!
# 烤這東西千萬別偷懶
Every effort counts when you're roasting food.
# 今稍微偷一下懶
I've just slacked off a bit today.
# 雞都烤的那個 太硬啦
And the pheasant is already, so hard.
# 硬邦邦的 肉都硬邦邦的
It's as hard as a stone. The meat is as hard as a stone.
# 味道還可以
But the tastes is not too bad.
# 還能吃的下去
I can still put it into my mouth.
# 真的很好吃
It's really tasty.
# 喜歡吃香的朋友
If you like jerky,
# 就把它烤成這個樣子 特別香
it would be exactly something that you love. It's smells really good.
# 像我就喜歡吃香的
By the way, I like jerky.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 今天的視頻到這裡啦
The video ends here.
# 把它搞回去
Let me take it back.
# 把這個火滅一下
I'm gonna put off the fire.
# 這個炭下次還可以用的
The charcoal can be taken back for next time.
# 拿這個裝點水
I take some water with it.
# 困難
Problem
# 辦法總比困難多
There are always more solutions than problems.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 那在慢慢就
Let it cool down,
# 沒那麼燙啦 火就滅掉啦
slowly. And then the fire will be off.
# 收拾一下
Let's tidy up everything,
# 準備回去啦
and get ready to go back.